ottolenghi.co.uk 2019-04-16

# Privacy Policy

This privacy policy sets out how we, Ottolenghi Ltd, use and protect any information that you give us when you use this website. By visiting www.ottolenghi.co.uk you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Privacy Policy and the Terms and Conditions.

We are committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

We may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You can check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from May 2013.

## 1\. What we collect

We will collect the following information when purchasing from our online store:

  * Your name.
  * Your contact information including shipping and credit card billing address(es), email address and phone number(s).
  * Demographic information about you, such as postcode.
  * A record of your purchase(s).

Card details will never be shared with third parties and will only be used to process your order, using our payment gateway system. Additionally we may also obtain information as a result of authentication or identity checks. We will ask for your telephone number to be given to our courier for delivery services. These details allow us to process your order and to let you know the status of your order.

Please note, we do **NOT** store your credit card information

## 2\. What we do with the information we gather

We require this information to be able to process your order and payment and to understand your needs and provide you with a better service. We may use the information to improve our products and services. Personal information that you provide may be disclosed to a credit reference or fraud prevention agency, which may keep a record of that information. Where there is a legal obligation to do so, we may disclose your information to any relevant regulatory body.

We may communicate with you about our latest news, events, products and special offers. At all times, we will offer you the opportunity to unsubscribe. Any email we send you will contain an easy automated unsubscribe link, simply follow the indications in the email.

We never sell your details to third party marketing companies. We do collate statistical information about site traffic, sales and other commercial information but these statistics do not include any information which can identify you personally.

## 3\. Security

WWe are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

## 4\. How we use cookies

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us. You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website. For more information on cookies and how to disable them, you can consult the information provided by the Interactive Advertising Bureau at www.allaboutcookies.org.

## 5\. Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over these other websites. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and these sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

## 6\. Controlling your personal information

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following way:

  * If you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or emailing us at webstore@ottolenghi.co.uk.

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so.

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. A small fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to [webstore@ottolenghi.co.uk](mailto:webstore@ottolenghi.co.uk)

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, email us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.
